<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.3/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.3/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.3.xsd" version="0.3" xml:lang="en">
  <siteinfo>
    <sitename>Eclipsepedia</sitename>
    <base>http://wiki.eclipse.org/Main_Page</base>
    <generator>MediaWiki 1.12.0</generator>
    <case>first-letter</case>
      <namespaces>
      <namespace key="-2">Media</namespace>
      <namespace key="-1">Special</namespace>
      <namespace key="0" />
      <namespace key="1">Talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="2">User</namespace>
      <namespace key="3">User talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="4">Eclipsepedia</namespace>
      <namespace key="5">Eclipsepedia talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="6">Image</namespace>
      <namespace key="7">Image talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="8">MediaWiki</namespace>
      <namespace key="9">MediaWiki talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="10">Template</namespace>
      <namespace key="11">Template talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="12">Help</namespace>
      <namespace key="13">Help talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="14">Category</namespace>
      <namespace key="15">Category talk</namespace>
    </namespaces>
  </siteinfo>
  <page>
    <title>OSEE/Users Guide/Features</title>
    <id>19201</id>
    <revision>
      <id>160198</id>
      <timestamp>2009-06-23T23:15:51Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ryan.schmitt.boeing.com</username>
        <id>5142</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Query Log */</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">=Component Overview=
==Application Framework==

'''Key Capabilities'''

* Dynamic and strongly typed artifact model (persistence layer)
* Bidirectional traceability through typed relations model
* Advanced version control including multi-level branching
* Subject-based and object-based Access Control
* User management and authentication
* Dynamic searching API
* Indexing and tagging services
* Views and editors for the creation, manipulation, and navigation of artifacts, attributes, and relations
* Remote event service for communication and synchronization of OSEE instances
* Rules framework for text processing
* Utilities for plug-in developers
* Scheduling framework
* API for the extension and use of this framework to build tightly integrated applications
* Encryption Utility
* Database Utilities
* Jini Utilities
* Scheduling Service
* Datastore Adapter

==Define - Requirements Management==

Define provides requirements and process management with tightly integrated change management using the Action Tracking System (ATS). OSEE provides publishing capabilities that enable the creation of documents from smaller internal documents to the complex documents needed to meet military requirements for contract deliverables such as the Software Requirements Specification (SRS), System Performance Specification (SPS), Prime Item Development Specification (PIDS), and all the required traceability between them.

'''Key Capabilities'''

* Enterprise support for concurrent, distributed requirements development
* Integrated process and workflow
* Programmatic, bidirectional traceability
* End user navigation and search capabilities
* Capture accurate, meaningful review metrics
* Tight integration with lifecycle tools
* Automated change detection capabilities

==Action Tracking System==

ATS is a tightly integrated change tracking system that manages changes throughout a product's lifecycle. ATS provides integrated change management to all OSEE applications through user customizable workflows.

'''Key Capabilities'''

* Built on same OSEE application framework as requirements, code, test development
* Common Workflow Framework that provides for the creation of any number of simple to complex workflow state machine configurations that can work together during the engineering lifecycle
* Workflows are configured through graphical diagrams that ATS uses at runtime
* Configuration of ATS performed through OSEE?s common application framework enabling workflows to be created and modified without separate OSEE releases
* Advanced project planning capabilities and release management
* Duplication errors are minimized as items are automatically linked and data is shared
* Menus, Views and Editors give access to ATS while working in any other aspect in OSEE
* ATS is used to track changes and support issues for the development of OSEE itself
* Bug Icon allows quick Action creation against any OSEE integrated tool

==Open Test Environment==

OTE is a powerful test solution within OSEE that integrates with existing Java, C, and C++ development environments to provide a seamless flow between developing, debugging, executing, and dispositioning of tests for complex hardware and software. The user is provided a common interface to the simulated and real-time environments for both functional and unit testing.

'''Key Capabilities'''

* Supports the execution of multiple simultaneous batches within a single workspace
* Built-in help system extended with test manger user guide
* Message system supporting MIL-STD-1553 MUX, serial, wire, Ethernet, and Data Distribution Service (DDS)
* Message GUIs provide monitoring, manipulation, and recording of messaging data
* Utilizes OSEE application framework to provide traceability to software requirements
* Automatic generation of tests and testing support classes, directly from requirements.
* Leverages off Java Development Toolkit (JDT) and C/C++ Development Toolkit (CDT)
* Provides remote execution of scripts against target hardware and operating system
* Test results are logged in XML
* Transforms test results via built-in or user supplied XSL Transformations
* Built-in XSL Transformations produce interactive HTML result reports
* A test environment service that provides both soft real-time and simulated capabilities, schedules the periodic execution of simulation components, and manages the I/O and testing resources.

==BLAM==

BLAM Lightweight Artifact Manipulation (BLAM) allows non-programmers to graphically construct workflows to automate repetitive tasks. A given workflow can be used for variety of similar tasks by using customizable controls to specify workflow parameters.

'''Key Capabilities'''

* Integrated management of charge/cost accounting
* Build planning and execution
* Reporting services
* Rules framework for requiring/alerting certain conditions
* Scheduling services for automating reoccurring tasks

====Program/Project Management====

Program and project management tightly integrated with the Action Tracking System and other OSEE components to provide services necessary for estimation, planning, execution, and delivery of products managed within OSEE.

==Discovery and Learning==

Services provided for allowing advanced learning and discovery using OSEE?s abundant and inherent lifecycle data and metrics.

'''Key Capabilities'''

* Discovery of inefficiencies in lifecycle processes
* Advanced data mining and data fusion
* Advanced estimating
* Advanced export/import of product capabilities between programs including applicable design, requirements, code, and test
* Advanced data visualization
* Prediction of future risks
* Simulation of recommended process and lifecycle changes

==Application Development==

Provide capabilities needed for external software application development plug-ins, like JDT, to utilize the OSEE persistence layer and integrate with other OSEE-based applications.

====Design and Modeling====

Provide capabilities needed for external design and modeling plug-ins to utilize the OSEE persistence layer and integrate with other OSEE-based applications.



=Views and Editors=
==Branch Manager View==

The Branch Manager View, shown by default in the Define Perspective, shows all branches and transactions on each branch managed by OSEE in a hierarchical fashion.  By default, OSEE is initialized with two branches. The System Root Branch (visible to OSEE Administrators only) and the Common Branch. The System Root Branch is the base branch for all other branches in the system. The Common branch is used to store system-wide artifacts such as configuration artifacts, users, and user preferences.

[[Image:branchManager.jpg|right]]

===Toolbar buttons===
{| class=&quot;wikitable&quot; style=&quot;border:1&quot;
|- style=&quot;background:#CCCCCC&quot;
!  Command
!  Description
|- 
| Refresh
| Refreshes the branch hierarchy tree with the latest branch information.
|- 
| Customize Table
| Opens the table customization dialog. This allows users to add or hide columns.
|- 
| ATS Bug
| Opens an action against the Branch Manager View.
|}

===Toolbar Drop-Down===
To display, click on the inverted triangle located on the upper right-hand side of the Branch Manager view.
{| class=&quot;wikitable&quot; style=&quot;border:1&quot;
|- style=&quot;background:#CCCCCC&quot;
!  Command
!  Description
|- 
| Branch Presentation
| Switch presentation between flat or hierarchical views.
|- 
| Show/Hide Archived Branches
| (Admins Only) Toggles archived branch visibility.
|- 
| Show/Hide Merged Branches
| (Admins Only) Toggles merge branch visibility.
|- 
| Show/Hide Transactions
| Toggles branch transaction visibility.
|- 
| Show Favorites First
| Orders branches by showing favorite branches first.
|}

===Pop-up Menu===

To display, perform a right-click on any branch.

{| class=&quot;wikitable&quot; style=&quot;border:1&quot;
|- style=&quot;background:#CCCCCC&quot;
!  Command
!  Description
|- 
| Explore
| Opens the Artifact Explorer View for the selected branch. This operation can also be performed by double-clicking on a branch.
|- 
| Change Report
| Opens the Change Report View for the selected branch.
|- 
| Merge Manager
| Opens the merge manager. This is used to resolve conflicts when committing a working branch back into its parent branch.
|- 
| Branch
| Creates a child branch of the selected branch.
|- 
| Commit Into
| Commits changes made to a branch into another branch.
|- 
| Delete Branch
| Deletes the selected branch from the system by setting the branch state to deleted. (Recoverable)
|- 
| Purge Branch
| Purges the selected branch from the system by removing all data from the data store. (Not recoverable)
|- 
| Purge Transaction
| Purges the currently selected transaction from its branch. Removes all changes made on the selected transaction. (Not recoverable)
|- 
| Open Associated Artifact
| Opens the artifact that was associated with the creation of the selected branch.
|- 
| Set Associated Artifact
| Associates an artifact with the currently selected branch.
|- 
| Access Control
| Opens the access control dialog.
|- 
| Rename
| Allows users to change the branch name.
|- 
| Rename Short Name
| Allows users to change the branch short name.
|- 
| Mark as Favorite
| Sets/Unsets a branch as a favorite branch.
|- 
| Copy
| Places branch information into the clipboard.
|- 
| Open Osee Data Model Editor
| Opens a graphical editor of all the artifact, attribute, and relation types in the system.
|- 
| Open Branch Graph
| Shows a graphical representation of branches using the currently selected branch as the base branch.
|}

==Artifact Explorer View==

The Artifact Explorer view, shown by default in the Define perspective, shows the artifact hierarchy of the selected branch.  The artifact hierarchy is derived from the artifact's default hierarchy relation.  By default, all branches have a default hierarchy root artifact which is the hierarchy tree's base element.  

[[Image:artifactExplorer.jpg|right]]

===Toolbar buttons===

{| class=&quot;wikitable&quot; style=&quot;border:1&quot;
|- style=&quot;background:#CCCCCC&quot;
!  Command
!  Description
|- 
| Collapse All
| Collapses all tree nodes.
|- 
| View Parent
| Navigates to the parent container of the artifacts that are currently displayed at the top level in the view.
|- 
| New Artifact Explorer
| Opens a new instance of the Artifact Explorer view.
|- 
| Change Report
| Opens the Change Report View for the Artifact Explorer's selected branch.  This report will show all changes made to the selected branch.
|- 
| Quick Search
| Opens the Quick Search View for the selected branch.
|- 
| ATS Bug
| Opens an action against the Artifact Explorer view.
|}


===Pop-up Menu===
To display, select one or more artifacts and perform a right-click.

{| class=&quot;wikitable&quot; style=&quot;border:1&quot;
|- style=&quot;background:#CCCCCC&quot;
!  Command
!  Description
|- 
| Open
| Opens the selected artifact using the default editor.
|- 
| Open With
| Opens a sub-menu listing the available editor's for this artifact.
|- 
| Reveal on Another Branch
| Open's a new instance of Artifact Explorer for a user selected branch. Expands tree elements to display the selected artifact to be revealed.
|- 
| New Child
| Creates a new artifact and places it directly under the selected artifact.
|- 
| Go Into
| Sets the selected artifact as the base of the artifact hierarchy tree hiding artifacts except child artifacts.
|- 
| Mass Edit
| Opens the Artifact Mass Editor populated with the selected artifacts.
|- 
| Delete Artifact
| Deletes the selected artifacts.
|- 
| Purge Artifact
| Purges the selected artifacts from the data store.
|- 
| Rename Artifact
| Allows a user to quickly change the artifact's name attribute.
|- 
| Show Resource History
| Opens the Resource History view for the selected artifact. This will display all transactions for this artifact.
|- 
| Import
| Opens Eclipse's import dialog.
|- 
| Export
| Opens Eclipse's export dialog.
|- 
| Lock
| Locks the artifact so the current user is the only one allowed to make changes to its attributes.
|- 
| Copy
| Copies the artifact.
|- 
| Paste
| Pastes the artifact.
|- 
| Expand All
| Expands all tree nodes from the selected artifact down.
|- 
| Select All
| Selects all open tree nodes.
|- 
| Access Control
| Opens the access control dialog.
|}

===Operations===

Operations that can be performed on an Artifact Explorer.
{| class=&quot;wikitable&quot; style=&quot;border:1&quot;
|- style=&quot;background:#CCCCCC&quot;
!  Command
!  Description
|- 
| Cross Branch Drag and Drop
| Artifacts can be referenced from other branches by dragging an artifact from one branch and dropping in onto another Artifact Explorer. The outcome will be one of two actions. If the artifact already existed on the branch it will be updated with the source artifacts state data. If the artifact did not exist on the destination branch it will be introduced to that branch. Meaning it will show up in the change report as an introduced artifact.
|- 
| File Document Drag and Drop
| Artifacts can be created by dragging and dropping files directly onto the parent artifact. After the drop is performed, the Artifact Import Wizard should open. Select the import method and artifact type to convert file into. This should create a child artifact directly under the artifact where the file was dropped.
|}

==Artifact Editor==

The Artifact editor provides specialized features for editing artifacts (this is the default editor for editing attributes and relations).  The editor can be opened through Artifact Explorer, by double-clicking on any artifact or right-clicking on an artifact and selecting to Open With &quot;Artifact Editor&quot;.


Associated with the editor is an Artifact-specific Outline view, which shows the structure of the active artifact.  It is updated as the user edits the artifact.

[[Image:artifactEditor.jpg|right]]

The Artifact Editor is divided into the following sections ''(some sections can be expanded and collapsed by clicking on the section's title bar)''. 

===1. Title Area===
#'''Artifact Name''' - the artifact's name attribute
#'''Message Area''' - reports issues that need to be addressed by the user before saving is allowed. Click on the message to open a message summary window. From the message summary window, click on any message to jump to the item associated with the message.
#'''Toolbar Area'''
{| class=&quot;wikitable&quot; style=&quot;border:1&quot;
|- style=&quot;background:#CCCCCC&quot;
!  Command
!  Description
|- 
| Refresh
| Refreshes the artifact editor. Displaying the artifact's current data. NOTE: Changes made to the form will be lost unless data is saved before clicking on this button.
|- 
| ATS Bug
| Opens an action against the Artifact Editor.
|- 
| Open the Artifact
| Opens the artifact or if clicking on the down-arrow, displays the open with sub-menu.
|- 
| Delete Artifact
| Deletes the artifact and closes the editor.
|- 
| Open Outline
| Displays the outline view.
|- 
| Open Resource History
| Opens the artifact's resource history.
|- 
| Reveal Artifact
| Displays the artifact in an Artifact Explorer view.
|- 
| Open Branch Manager
| Open the Branch Manager View and highlights the artifact's branch.
|- 
| Lock/Unlock
| Locks/Unlocks the artifact for editting. When locked, it prevents other user's from making changes to the artifact.
|- 
| Copy Url
| Copies a link to the latest version of the artifact to the clipboard.
|}

===2. Artifact Information Area===
Displays the artifact's branch, artifact type, and human readable id.

===3. Attributes Section===
Displays attribute types to be edited. Attribute types can be added or deleted by clicking on the appropriate toolbar button ''located on the upper-right of the attributes section title bar''.
'''Note: The following operations follow min/max occurrence rules defined by the attribute's type.'''
{| class=&quot;wikitable&quot; style=&quot;border:1&quot;
|- style=&quot;background:#CCCCCC&quot;
!  Command
!  Description
|- 
| Add
| Opens a dialog displaying attribute types that can be added to the artifact.
|-
| Delete
| Opens a dialog displaying attribute types that can be deleted from the artifact. '''Note: Data entered for the attribute type to be deleted will be lost as soon as the dialog's '''OK''' button is selected.
|}

===4. Relations Section===
All relations that are defined as being valid for the artifact are shown. Relations can be added by dragging any set of artifacts into the appropriate relation group.  Relations can be deleted by right-click &quot;Delete Relation&quot; ''(removes the link, but not the artifact)''. Opening relation groups will show all artifacts that are currently related.  Double-clicking a related artifact will open it in it's default editor (normally the Artifact Editor).

'''Pop-up Menu''' - To display, expand the Relations section, select one or more artifacts, and perform a right-click.
{| class=&quot;wikitable&quot; style=&quot;border:1&quot;
|- style=&quot;background:#CCCCCC&quot;
!  Command
!  Description
|-
| Open
| Opens the selected artifacts using the default editor.
|-
| Open With
| Opens a sub-menu listing the available editor's for the selected artifact.
|-
| Edit
| Opens the Artifact for editing.
|-
| Mass Edit
| Opens the Artifact Mass Editor populated with the selected artifacts.
|-
| View Relation Table
| Opens an HTML report of the relation tree.
|-
| Order Relation
| (Future Capability)
|-
| Delete Relation
| Deletes the selected relations.
|-
| Expand All
| Expands all tree nodes containing relations to this artifact.
|-
| Select All
| Selects all tree nodes.
|-
| Delete Artifact
| Deletes the selected artifact and its relation to this artifact.
|}


===5. Details Section===
Displays artifact meta-data.

==Resource History View==

The resource history view allows users to view the detailed changes to an aritfact.

[[Image:resourcehistoryview.jpg]]

In addition, the view also provides the user with the ability to select and compare artifacts.

[[Image:resourcehistoryviewmenu2.jpg]]

== Mass Artifact Editor ==

The Mass Artifact Editor allows the easy view of multiple artifacts along with their attributes. This editor can be viewed by right clicking the Artifact Explorer, the Search Results page, or via ATS action. Single cells can be edited via Alt-Left-Mouse-Click. After editing any number of artifacts shown, the save button persists this data.

[[Image:masseditorview.jpg]]

See [http://wiki.eclipse.org/OSEE/Users_Guide#XViewer_-_Advanced_TreeViewer_Widget Xviewer] for more information

== Quick Search View ==

The Quick Search view allows users to perform searches for information that is contained ''inside'' artifacts in a selected branch.

[[Image:QuickSearchView.png]]

To find all artifacts that contain a particular set of keywords, select &lt;b&gt;Window &amp;gt; Show View &amp;gt; Other... &amp;gt; OSEE &amp;gt; Quick Search&lt;/b&gt; to open the view and type your search string in the &lt;b&gt;Enter Search String&lt;/b&gt; combo box (or use the pull-down list to select a previously entered search expression). 

If the &lt;i&gt;By Id&lt;/i&gt; option is selected, only spaces and commas are treated as delimiters. Otherwise, the following special characters are also treated as delimiters:

&lt;pre&gt;!&quot;#$%()*+-./:;&lt;&gt;?@][\^{|}~_&lt;/pre&gt;

For example:
      
* When &lt;i&gt;By Id&lt;/i&gt; is not selected, &lt;b&gt;&lt;code&gt;hello.world&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/b&gt; will be translated to &lt;b&gt;&lt;code&gt;hello&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;&lt;code&gt;world&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/b&gt;. The search will match attributes with &lt;b&gt;&lt;code&gt;hello&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;&lt;code&gt;world&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/b&gt; keywords.
* When &lt;i&gt;By Id&lt;/i&gt; is selected, (&lt;b&gt;&lt;code&gt;A+ABG7jFm+0BKaVZIxfqOQ,AFABG7jFm+0BKaVZIxfqOQ PX1FH&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/b&gt;) will be interpreted as 2 GUID(s) and 1 HRID. The search will match artifacts containing &lt;b&gt;&lt;code&gt;A+ABG7jFm+0BKaVZIxfqOQ&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;&lt;code&gt;AFABG7jFm+0BKaVZIxfqOQ&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/b&gt; as its GUID or &lt;b&gt;&lt;code&gt;PX1FH&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/b&gt; as its HRID.

 Finish entering your search options and click &lt;b&gt;Search&lt;/b&gt; or press &lt;b&gt;Enter&lt;/b&gt; from the combo box to execute the search. The Search view displays the results of your search. Right-click on any item in the Search view to open a context menu that allows you perform various operations on the artifacts such as copy search results to the clipboard or reveal a selected artifact in Artifact Explorer. To open one of the listed artifacts, double-click it or select &lt;b&gt;Open&lt;/b&gt; from the context menu.

==Sky Walker View==

==Change Report View==

The change report view shows all changes made to a branch.
 
[[Image:changereport.JPG|right]]

===Toolbar buttons===
{| class=&quot;wikitable&quot; style=&quot;border:1&quot;
|- style=&quot;background:#CCCCCC&quot;
!  Command
!  Description
|- 
| Refresh
| Refreshes the data in the change report view with the latest information.
|-
| Customize Table
| Opens the table customization dialog. This allows users add or hide columns.
|-
| ATS Bug
| Opens an action against the Change Report View.
|}

===Toolbar Drop-Down===

To display, click on the inverted triangle located on the upper right-hand side of the Change Report View.
{| class=&quot;wikitable&quot; style=&quot;border:1&quot;
|- style=&quot;background:#CCCCCC&quot;
!  Command
!  Description
|- 
| Show Document Order
| Switch presentation to show artifacts ordered by their default hierarchy relation.
|}

===Pop-up Menu===

To display, perform a right-click on any branch.

{| class=&quot;wikitable&quot; style=&quot;border:1&quot;
|- style=&quot;background:#CCCCCC&quot;
!  Command
!  Description
|- 
| Open
| Opens the selected artifact using the default editor.
|- 
| Open With
| Opens a sub-menu listing the available editor's for this artifact.
|- 
| Reveal in Artifact Explorer
| Displays an artifacts location in the Artifact Explorer.
|- 
| Resource History
| Opens the Resource History view for the selected artifact. This will display all transactions for this artifact.
|- 
| View Word Change Report
| Displays a Word document populated with the branch differences of the selected artifacts.
|- 
| View Viewer Report
| Generates a report of the Change Report View content.
|- 
| Copy
| Copies the artifact.
|- 
| Revert Artifact
| Reverts an artifact.
|- 
| Revert Attribute
| Reverts an attribute.
|- 
| Delete Transaction
| Deletes a transaction.
|}

==Query Log==

===Query Log View===

[[Image:Query_log_view.gif]]

====Purpose====

The Query Log view is used to review queries that have been run for the purpose of debugging. Details about the query such as how long it took to run, if any bind variables were passed, or if an SQL Exception was thrown while attempting to execute the query are all available. Run time is only reported for queries that executed successfully.

Queries can be sorted by clicking on the column heading for the column to sort by. Initially, the data will be sorted in ascending order. Clicking the same column multiple times will toggle the sorting between ascending and descending. The table can be sorted on multiple columns by holding the CTRL key and selecting columns in the order which they should be sorted.

====Shortcuts====

;CTRL+A
:Select all items displayed
;CTRL+C
:Copies the current selected item to the clipboard:
::SQL Item: Copies the full SQL Text
::Bind Variable: Copies the bind variable value, not including the type. Binary data not supported
::Exception: Copies the exception and stack trace
;CTRL+X
:Fully expand selected items

===Delete Query Log===

====Purpose====

Deletes all of the recorded queries from the log then refreshes the view. The log has a max capacity and once it is met no more entries will be added, so deleting the log will be necessary to see any new queries that are being performed. 

====How to do it====

Select the delete button ([[Image:delete_edit.gif]]) from the toolbar on the top portion of the Query Log view.

===Refresh Query Log===

====Purpose====

Repopulates the view with the latest information from the query log. The log has a max capacity and once it is met no more entries will be added. This can be taken care of by deleting the log contents (see above).

====How to do it====

Select the refresh button ([[Image:refresh.gif]]) from the toolbar on the top portion of the Query Log view.

=Services=

==Event Service==

OSEE is a client side application that runs off an Oracle database.  As with many applications, OSEE caches some of the data it provides to the user.  These caches need to be notified that there are updates available.  These updates are triggered by an event service that â€œconnectsâ€? all OSEE instances and notifies them that changes have been made to cached data.

When your application focus is on any OSEE View, you will notice a gear icon at the bottom of your workbench.  When NOT connected to the event service, this icon will show a red slash.   When this happens, you should shutdown, restart and accept all OSEE updates.  If this does not solve the problem, contact an OSEE Team member for help in resolving the problem.

==Attribute Tagging for Quick Search==

When an artifact is saved, each attribute contained in the artifact is analyzed to produce a list of tags that are then associated with the artifact. Quick search is a form of &lt;i&gt;keyword&lt;/i&gt; based searching which uses tags to perform contextual artifact searches.

For an attribute to be tagged by the system, it must meet the following criteria:

* The attribute's type must specify an &lt;b&gt;Attribute Tagger&lt;/b&gt; to be used by the tagging system.
* The attribute must contain valid data.
* The attribute revision must be saved in the database before sending to tagging system.

To produce tags, modified attributes are sent to the OSEE application server where the tagging system processes each attribute using an &lt;b&gt;Attribute Tagger&lt;/b&gt; specified by the attribute's type. The &lt;b&gt;Attribute Tagger&lt;/b&gt; knows how to interpret the attribute's data and how to extract words from the content. At this point, a word is defined as a sequential set of alphanumeric characters delimited by one or more spaces. As words are parsed, they are sent to the tagging system's word encoder where the following processing takes place:
   
* The characters in the original word are converted to lower case.
* The lowercase version of the word is encoded and stored in the tagging system.
* The lowercase version of the word is split using [[Users_Guide#Quick_Search_View|punctuation characters]] as delimiters.
* Words given in inflected form (possessive, plural, etc) are converted into [http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dictionary_form citation form].
* Each word is encoded and stored in the tag system.

When encoding words into tags, the tag encoder uses an algorithm which transforms the word's characters into a bit-packed tag that will fit in a 64-bit integer. The tag will represent up to 12 characters (all that can fit into 64-bits). Longer words will be turned into consecutive tags.

===Tag Encoding Examples===

{| class=&quot;wikitable&quot; border=&quot;1&quot;
|-
!Original
!Keywords
!Encoding
|-
|appendices
|appendix
|&amp;#45;220858502
|-
|batteries
|battery
|529513131
|-
|alternate
|alternate
|&amp;#45;1420231874
|-
|backup
|backup
|24902827
|}

=Custom Widgets=

==XViewer - Advanced TreeViewer Widget==

[http://www.eclipse.org/osee/xviewer/XViewer.pdf EclipseCon 2009 Presentation Slides]
[http://www.eclipse.org/osee/xviewer/org_eclipse_nebula_widgets_xviewer.zip Download Zip of Code and Example]
[http://www.eclipse.org/osee/xviewer/README.txt Download Instructions]

The purpose of the XViewer is to give the application developer a more advanced and dynamic TreeViewer that has the filtering and sorting the capabilities of a spreadsheet while providing the users the ability to customize their table to suit their current needs and save/restore these customizations for future use by individual or group.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

The current XViewer already commited as part of the [http://www.eclipse.org/osee/ Eclipse OSEE Project].
More information is available at [http://www.eclipse.org/osee/documentation/core/xviewer/xviewer.php OSEE XViewer].
There are near term plans to submit this to the Nebula project.

[[Image:Xviewer_main.PNG]]

&lt;h3&gt;Table Customizations&lt;/h3&gt;
*Provides '''table customization dialog''' to allow customization of visible columns, widths and renaming of columns
*'''Easily reorder columns''' through drag/drop or table customization
*Provides mechanism to '''save and load table customizations''' so users can easily switch between customizations
*Provides mechanism to '''mark table customizations as individual or global '''to provide sharing of customizations by users and teams (needs to be backed with shared file system or database)
*Provides mechanism to '''mark table customization as default customization''' to display whenever this table is shown
*Provides ability for '''multiple XViewer tables to be used within the same application''', but provide their own columns and customiztions

&lt;h3&gt;Sorting&lt;/h3&gt;
*Sort individual columns (forward or reverse) using '''data-specific configured sorter''' for that columns data type
*Perform unlimited '''multi-column sorting''' by holding Ctrl key down and selecting other columns.  Re-selecting a column while Ctrl is held down will reverse the sort for that column

&lt;h3&gt;Filtering&lt;/h3&gt;
*'''Quick filter (bottom left)''' provides for filtering of all visible data by entered keywords
*Alt-left click on column header (or right-click menu) allows for '''filtering by column'''.  As many column filters can be added and work together.
*Provides '''simple metrics (bottom status label)''' to show number of objects loaded, number shown and number selected.
*'''Status label shows filters and sorters''' that are currently applied to viewer (bottom status label)

&lt;h3&gt;Other Capabilities&lt;/h3&gt;
*Provides ability to '''copy rows, columns or individual cells into buffer''' for pasting into other applications
*Allows for '''multi-column editing of selected rows/columns'''
*Provides '''html rendering''' of currently visible table data
*Provides '''comma separated value export''' to csv file that can be opened in any spreadsheet application
*All the normal capabilities of the existing SWT Tree/TreeViewer have been retained as XViewer is an extension to TreeViewer

&lt;h3&gt;Future&lt;/h3&gt;
*'''Submitted to Nebula''' as alternative to existing SWT TreeViewer (already part of eclipse.org/osee project)
*Allow for '''advanced column filtering''' by complex expression and &quot;canned list&quot; of already entered items
*Add '''regular expressions''' to all filtering capabilities
*Provide easy ability to '''sum selected rows for selected column'''
*Provide simple '''summing/counting of rows/column''' data
*Provide '''formulas and functions''' for advanced summing/counting of data
*Provide '''graphing and charting''' of data
*Collaborate with other table/tree solutions to integrate functionality... 

&lt;h3&gt;Table Customizations&lt;/h3&gt;
[[Image:Xviewer_customize.PNG]]

&lt;h3&gt;Sorting and Filtering&lt;/h3&gt;
[[Image:Xviewer_sortfilter.PNG]]

&lt;h3&gt;HTML Report and CSV Export&lt;/h3&gt;
[[Image:Xviewer_reportexport.PNG]]

[[Category:OSEE]]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
